[Music]
well you know uh John one of the things
I wanted to talk to you about uh is your
own case because uh people know that
you're a whistleblower but people may
not know that there's been a kind of
bipartisan uh refusal to Pardon you for
whistleblowing and I mean it's
disgusting you blew the whistle on on
the cia's torture program your your
punishment for that your prize for being
honest and exposing something like that
is being uh thrown into jail thrown into
prison losing your pension yeah that's
the big part yeah and I mean well I I
assume as someone who hasn't been um
subjected to either of those Horrors I
assume they must both be extremely
traumatic and and traumatizing and the
idea that the only person to pay a price
is the person not who engaged in the
torture but blew the whistle on it can
you shed a little bit of light onto how
that happened then I want to ask you
about the pardon process because you
actually wrote a an article uh on the
defunct pardon process which you call
for change and you explain what needs to
happen so can can you unpack all of that
I threw a lot at you no that's okay so I
uh I gave a nationally televised
interview to ABC News in December of
2007 in which I said that the CIA was
torturing its prisoners that torture was
official US government policy and that
the policy had been personally approved
by the president this is when it goes
into the Twilight Zone the very next day
the CIA filed what's called a crimes
report report against me with the FBI
saying that I had um revealed classified
information top secret information in
this
interview um the FBI investigated me for
a year from December of 07 to December
of ' 08 and they uh finally sent my
attorneys what's called a declination
letter declining to prosecute me they
said that uh it was illegal to classify
a criminal act torture was a criminal
act and so I had not committed a crime
by revealing it
great I'm home free three weeks later
Barack Obama becomes president and he
names John Brennan as the deputy
National Security adviser for
counterterrorism John and I always hated
each other and one of the dirty little
secrets was that John Brennan was one of
the fathers of the cia's torture program
he pretended to be you know a
progressive Democrat he never was he was
a pro torture um
independent so I had no idea that as
soon as he was uh given this position of
Deputy National Security adviser he
asked the justice department to secretly
reopen the case against me in Discovery
later on we we found three memos there
was a memo from Brennan to Eric Holder
the Attorney General saying charge him
with
Espionage and holder wrote back and said
my people don't think he committed
Espionage and then Brennan wrote back
and said charge him anyway and make him
defend himself and so they charged me
with three counts of Espionage mind you
Espionage can carry the death penalty
right and um and then when I went
bankrupt they dropped the charges so I
ended up taking a plea to a a lesser
charge but I I was looking at my phone a
minute ago so I could pull this up I
received this email anonymously a month
ago and it says Dear John it's nice to
finally write to you I've been watching
your YouTube videos and I love all the
content and I've been wanting to reach
out to you for many years I'm one of the
FBI agents who wants to personally
apologize to you for the disgraceful way
that the FBI and our government treated
you I worked with both headquarters and
the Washington field office team on your
case and I know many of the Personnel
that you're familiar with that case was
directed and driven by senior most
officials many mid-level and Street
Personnel were against it but
nevertheless we just followed orders
anyway I've always felt bad about what
we did to you and for you and for the
way you were treated and I want wanted
to personally apologize sincerely Joe
wow that's the third one of those I've
gotten the third one so you know when
you embarrass the CIA and you air the
dirty laundry there's going to be a very
heavy price to pay it cost me literally
everything my my marriage my career my
freedom uh my children it cost
everything which is the the plan right
right one of my attorneys said to me
well in the midst of all this they said
you know this case isn't isn't just
about John kiraku this case is about
frightening anybody else in the
intelligence Community who might be
thinking about coming forward to report
on criminal activity inside the
organization and that's true you know Ed
Snowden said that uh Tom Drake and I
inspired him to go public with his uh
with his Revelations and that meant the
world to me and knowing that there are
other whistleblowers out there who who
you know if they don't go to the media
they go to the oversight committees or
they go to an attorney or whatever that
makes it all worthwhile now the the
pardon process I applied for a pardon
with Barack Obama I was ignored I knew I
would be then I applied for a pardon
from Donald Trump in Trump's first term
and I was I was close and it made the
papers a couple times once because Rudy
Giuliani tried to shake me down for $2
million and I ratted him out to the New
York Times and it made the front page I
don't think I know this story oh this
was a big one so I have a friend who is
close to Giuliani and people kept saying
oh you're close but if Giuliani gives
you the thumbs up Trump's gonna give it
to you I said okay how do I get to
Giuliani well I know this guy and he
works for Giuliani so I called him and
he said okay let's meet up at the Trump
Hotel um you and your lawyer Giuliani
and me I said great so we go to the
Trump Hotel giuliani's there and um
we're sitting there and and Giuliani
says uh so you know the Mets are looking
good this year and I'm like yeah great
uh are you a football fan I said yeah I
I'm a Steelers fan I understand you're a
Giants fan yeah I love the Giants I'm
like what the [__] is going on finally I
said so Mr Mayor I appreciate you taking
the time to see me but I wanted to talk
about this pardon and he says like this
anybody know where the pisser is and he
gets up and he walks away I said to the
guy what just happened and he said you
never talked to Rudy about a pardon you
talked to me about a pardon and I talk
to Rudy I'm like okay whatever like
these guys watch too many episodes of
The Sopranos so um he says Rudy's gonna
want two million and I laughed and I
said I said look I don't have two
million I'll never have 2 million but
why would I spend $2 million to cover a
$700,000 pension that doesn't make any
sense I said look I don't want to waste
your time I appreciate you uh seeing me
and I got up my lawyer and we walked
away so that night a friend of mine had
a book launch party and I went to the
party and there was another
whistleblower there that I'm friendly
with and he said to me innocently he
said so how was your day I said oh how
was my day listen to this I said Rudy
Giuliani tried to shake me down for two
million bucks and I told him and he said
did you call the FBI and I said I don't
talk to those those rats at the FBI I'm
I'm not a snitch right I didn't call the
FBI a couple days later I happened to be
standing in my attorney's office we were
chatting and my phone rang and it was
Mike Schmidt from The New York Times and
he said that a little birdie had told
him that Rudy Giuliani tried to shake me
down for $2 million was that true so I
said hold on a second I said to my
lawyer should I talk to the New York
Times he said yeah tell him the truth so
I said yeah I'll talk to you he said
will you go in the record I said sure
use my name I told him the whole story
and um he said actually you're the
fourth person that he he approached and
tried to take $2 million from for a
pardon and it's because he was getting a
divorce he was a member of 16 country
clubs he spent $10,000 a month on cigars
and he needed this money to continue you
know the lifestyle to which he had grown
accustomed no wonder has that terrible
hair dye he couldn't afford a good
hairdress down his face yeah exactly he
does you know just for men or whatever
the spray is so um he denied and denied
and denied he he said that he had never
met me that he hadn't been in Washington
that day so I sent the New York Times a
picture of the four of us together that
we took in the lobby and they wrote The
New York Times has seen documentary
evidence that the meeting took place
when um Noel I forget her last name his
assistant went public about her her
sexual harassment case she said that he
told her the day of the New York Times
article that that son of a [__] CIA guy
ratted me out to the times and I said
yep I did so a long way of saying
Giuliani didn't help me but I got that
close because Tucker Carlson helped me
right I had been on Tucker show a dozen
times he loves when I criticized the
agency we we became friends and he went
to Trump for me and he said he's going
to do it then on the last day of the
Trump presidency Tucker called me and
said that Mitch McConnell had called him
and killed it because Mitch McConnell
said that if Trump pardoned and this was
the original idea Trump was gonna pardon
Julian Assange Ed Snowden and me that
and and McConnell didn't know me but he
said if Trump uh pardoned Assange and
Snowden that he couldn't control the
Republican caucus in the Senate and that
they would probably vote to convict him
on the impeachment charges so he dropped
our pardons then I go to Biden and I'm
friendly with a Greek Orthodox priest
who is very very close to Joe Biden he
said I can help
you so I'm getting you know this guy to
write a letter and that guy to write a
letter and Senator soand so and
Congressman what's his name and I got I
got a Anette Benning and and I got Susan
Sarandon and Mike Ferell and I got a
whole Hollywood contingent and then he
passed me over and I said to the priest
because the priest was like nobody's as
close to him as I am I'm I'm Hunter's
Godfather you know blah blah blah and I
said well if I had been a crackhead or a
Chinese spy or a judge that sold
children into bondage maybe I would have
I would have gotten so [__] Joe Biden
excuse me language and one of those kids
killed himself by the way one of the kid
one
of cash for kids you are exactly correct
he killed himself he was like 16 years
old yeah and so I'm trying with Trump
again and without even
trying um Alan dtz called me and said
hey are you gonna are you gonna apply
for a pardon I said yeah I'd like to I
said I'm I'm kind of disillusioned now
and he said no he said I'll write a
letter and then we can circulate it and
maybe get some some other people to sign
so I got I got Alan dtz I got Tucker
Carlson I got judge napalitano and two
two high ranking friends of trump that
nobody's ever heard of in in this venue
um and so we're gonna go again and I'm
gonna I'm gonna try my best we'll see
what happens but you know I I like to
think that I'm going to get a fair shake
from the Republicans on this because it
was Barack Obama and John Brennan and
Eric Holder that put me in prison and
covered up war crimes and crimes against
humanity it was not Donald Trump we
there are a lot of things we can
criticize Donald Trump over sure but
this is not one of them